[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：关于练习三的问题。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Questions about exercise three.
是吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好吧，
Yes? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Well,
我有p1然后函数，和
I have p1 then functions, and
然后我把它放在选项下面。
then I have that under the options.
我[INAUDIBLE]。
I [INAUDIBLE].
&gt；&gt；Kyle：那么，你是说把圆点放在这里？
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So, you're saying put the dot then here?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我把它放在[INAUDIBLE]下。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I put it under [INAUDIBLE].
&GT；&GT；Kyle：你是这个意思吗？
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Is that what you're saying?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[听不见]像这样吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [INAUDIBLE] Like that?
[听不见]那么功能，没有，
[INAUDIBLE] Then functions, no,
这就发生了，函数输出。&gt；&gt；Kyle：你是
this happened then, functions output. &gt;&gt; Kyle: You're
说你把这个拿出来了。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的。
saying you took this one out. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：您确实输出了文本。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: You did output text.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的，并且
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes, and
然后返回p2。&gt；&gt；Kyle：和
then return p2. &gt;&gt; Kyle: And
然后返回p2，对吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的。
then return p2 is that correct? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：有效的解决方案，但是
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Valid solution, but
这并不是以承诺链为导向的。
that's not as promise chain oriented.
我更喜欢保持输出和链接在不同的地方。
I would prefer to keep the output and the chaining in separate places.
分别进行推理的步骤。
Separate steps to reason about.
这将在功能上工作，但这不是我个人喜欢的风格。
This will functionally work, but this isn't the style I would personally prefer.
我更喜欢步骤更明确地分开的样式。
I prefer a style where the steps are more explicitly separate.
你要考虑一下，这只是一般的编程实践。
You wanna think about, this is just general programming practice.
功能应该是尽可能单一的用途。
Functions should be as single purpose as possible.
所以，不要让一个函数做两件完全不同的事情，
So, don't make a function that does two entirely separate things,
输出前一个响应，并对另一件事进行排序。
outputting the response from a previous one, and sequencing in yet another thing.
这两个任务是不同的关注点，在我看来，它们属于，
Those two tasks are separate concerns, and they belong, in my opinion,
链条中的一个单独的步骤。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：那么，
a separate steps in the chain. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So,
你需要解析逗号拼接？
you need to resolve the comma splice?
然后你有两个THEN语句
And then you have two then statements for
P1有两次结果吗？&gt；&gt；Kyle：否。
p1 there to result twice? &gt;&gt; Kyle: No.
问题是，如果我说在我的程序中的其他地方，如果我有另一个p1，
The question was, if I said somewhere else in my program, if I had another p1.,
例如，然后是logValue。
then logValue, for example.
所以现在我有两个p1.then‘s。
So now I have two p1.then's.
我在同一个承诺上注册了两个处理者。
I register two then handlers on the same promise.
这和下链不是一回事，因为这是一个不同的承诺。
That's not the same thing as off the chain, cuz this is a different promise.
但在这里，我有两个当时的操纵者在同一个承诺中注册。
But here, I have two then's handlers registered in the same promise.
解析需要被调用两次吗？
Does resolve need to get called twice?
绝对不行。
Absolutely not.
调用Resolve一次，承诺就会解析为该值
You call resolve once, and the promise becomes resolved to that value
立即且永远不变，无论您是事先观察还是
immediately and forever immutable, no matter whether you observe beforehand or
在手之后，不管你观察了多少次。
after hand, and no matter how many times you observe it.
你还是会得到相同的值。
You're still going to get that same value.
就像我们的屁股一样。
It's exactly like with our thunks.
例如，每次我们调用thunk，我们都会得到相同的25值。
Every time we call the thunk, we're gonna get that same 25 value out, for example.
因此，在这里，只有一个解析，并且日志值和输出都将被调用
So here, only one resolve, and both log value and output would get called with
这个值，以及我们称为p1.then的任何未来时间。
that value, as well as any future times that we called p1.then.
是吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器4：我有点困惑
Yes? &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: I'm a little confused about
输出返回的内容如下
what the output returns so
你可以把它锁起来。&gt；&gt；Kyle：每次使用Then方法时，
that you can chain it. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Every time the then method,
这涉及到了一些实现细节。
this is getting a little bit into the implementation details.
每次调用Then方法时，
Every single time that then method is called,
实际上，它确实回报了自己的承诺。
it actually does return its own promise.
所以，当我在37号线上链条的时候，
So, when I chain right here on line 37,
我正在链接一个由该方法创建并返回的新承诺。
I am chaining off a new promise that was created and returned by that method.
默认情况下，该新承诺设置为立即解决。
That new promise is set to, by default, be resolved immediately.
除非上一步返回另一个承诺，在这种情况下它有点劫持。
Unless the previous step returns another promise, in which case it sort of hijacks.
这就是我说的掩护下的复杂的东西，看起来很简单
That's that complicated under the cover stuff that I said, seems simple and
实际上相当复杂。
it's actually pretty complex.
这部分已经为你处理好了。
That part's handled for you.
因此，这将自动链接到一个新的
So, this is automatically chaining off of a new
我保证。&gt；&gt；扬声器4：那么，
promise. &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: So,
该函数的输入是什么？
what would the input to that function be?
嗯，它将是-&gt；&gt；Kyle：因为我们不退货
Well, it would be- &gt;&gt; Kyle: Because we don't return anything
从输出。
from output.
如果我返回类似于，你好，
If I returned something like, hello there,
我从承诺中返回的价值
that value that I'm returning from that promise
会自动通过管道进入并进入这里是一个论点。
would automatically get piped in and come in here is an argument.
但是因为我没有从输出中返回任何东西，所以什么都不会发生。
But since I'm not returning anything from output, nothing goes.
&gt；&gt；扬声器4：所以它是未定义的？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: So it's undefined?
&GT；&GT；Kyle：嗯，它是一样的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Well, it's the same,
所有没有Return的JavaScript函数都与Return相同
all JavaScript functions that don't have a return are the same thing as return
未定义。
undefined.
是吗？&GT；&GT；扬声器5：他们在问，
Yeah? &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: They're asking,
是函数或传递给。然后是值
is the function or passing to .then the value
结果呢？&gt；&gt；Kyle：没有。
of result? &gt;&gt; Kyle: No.
我不明白这个问题，但是
I don't understand the question, but
我知道答案是否定的。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：那么，我认为他是
I know that that it's the answer is no. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: So, I think he is
问输出，它的值是多少？&gt；&gt；Kyle：我需要知道行号
asking output, what is the value of that? &gt;&gt; Kyle: I need to know a line number
有人问起的事情。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：我36岁。
that somebody is asking about. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: I'm 36.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：第36行。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Line 36.
什么的价值是什么？
What is the value of what?
输出函数的值，或
The value of the output function, or
.Then函数的值？&gt；&gt；扬声器5：解析在哪里
the value of the .then function? &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Where is the resolve
定义？&gt；&gt；Kyle：此处定义了解析。
defined? &gt;&gt; Kyle: Resolve is defined here.
它通过Promise机制传递到我们的Promise构造函数中。
It's passed into our promise constructor by the promise mechanism.
我们要做的就是打电话给它。
All we have to do is call it.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 6：前面的示例，其中
&gt;&gt; Speaker 6: The previous example where
你有一个p1，然后用log记录结果。&gt；&gt；Kyle：嗯哼。
you had a p1.then with log on the result. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Uh-huh.
&GT；&GT；演讲者6：顺序是什么？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 6: What's the order?
它是先执行输出还是
Would it execute output first or
先登录？&gt；&gt；Kyle：订单将是
log first? &gt;&gt; Kyle: The order will be
如果你有两个不同的，那么相同的承诺，这就是我们在这里。
if you have two different then's on the same promise, which is what we have here.
请记住，第39行不再是。然后在p1上。
Keep in mind line 39 is not a .then on p1 anymore.
这是完全不同的承诺。
It's on a different promise entirely.
但是第38行和第35行是在同一个承诺上。
But line 38 and line 35 are then's on the same promise.
在这些情况下，他们首先进入，首先登记，执行顺序。
In those cases, they go in first, registered first, executed order.
不过，你真的不应该关注这种细节。
You really should not pay any attention to that sort of detail, though.
&gt；&gt；扬声器6：[笑]
&gt;&gt; Speaker 6: [LAUGH]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：你真的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: You really, really,
真的绝对不应该。
really absolutely should not.
关于某物在承诺上登记的订单的原因，
Reason about what order something was registered on the promise in,
并不是说它不可靠，它是，这是由规范保证的。
not that it's not reliable, it is, that's guaranteed by the spec.
这是糟糕的编程实践。
This is terrible programming practice.
这就回到了我们正在讨论的那些前函数式编程概念
That's way back to those pre functional programming concepts that we're talking
关于你不能理解你的系统状态的地方，
about where you can't understand the state of your system,
因为你不是一下子就看清了一切。
cuz you don't see it all at once.
所以，承诺邀请你接受你正在处理的想法
So, promises invite you to embrace the idea that you are dealing with
你不应该做的独立的事情。
independent things that you shouldn't.
不应在分辨率之间建立依赖关系
You should not build dependency between the resolution
如果你能避免的话。
of promise handlers if you can avoid it.
&gt；&gt；扬声器6：就在那里。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 6: Right there.
他在跟进他的问题，但他，我不知道我们从哪里经过
He's kind of following up on his question, but he's, I don't see where we pass
将解决价值转化为承诺。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：这给了我们-
the resolve value into the promise. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: That gives us-
&gt；&gt；Kyle：解决值，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The resolve value,
我想也许我只是，也许只是，
I think maybe I'm just, it's maybe being just,
很难理解这些问题被问的方式。
it's hard to understand the way the questions are being asked.
我认为实际上被问到的是你没有在第24行看到这个事实，
I think what's actually being asked is you not seeing the fact that this on line 24,
这个解析函数是我们假Ajax中的CB。
this resolve function is that CB up here in our fake AJAX.
下面是我们调用result函数的地方
And down here is where we're calling the result function and
正在传递文本。&gt；&gt；扬声器7：这就是输出。
passing text in. &gt;&gt; Speaker 7: And that is output.
输出是函数？&gt；&gt；Kyle：否。
Output is a function? &gt;&gt; Kyle: No.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：不？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: No?
凯尔：不，不。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: No, no, no, no, no.
Resolve是传递给假Ajax的东西。
Resolve is the thing that's getting passed into fake Ajax.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：不是输出。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Not output.
&gt；&gt；扬声器4：但是我们通过了
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: But we're passing
功能。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：函数
the function. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Function with
响应和解决与响应。
the response and resolve with response.
这更有意义吗？
Does that make more sense?
在第24行？&gt；&gt；Kyle：这样会不会更容易
On line 24? &gt;&gt; Kyle: Does that make it easier to
明白吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器4：和
understand? &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: And
结果未输出。&gt；&gt；Kyle：不，结果来自承诺
result is not output. &gt;&gt; Kyle: No, result comes from the promise
构造函数。&gt；&gt；Kyle：这
constructor. &gt;&gt; Kyle: This
内置于JavaScript中。&gt；&gt；扬声器4：是的。
is built into JavaScript. &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Yep.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：它产生一个函数，我们
&gt;&gt; Kyle: It produces a function that we
碰巧呼叫解决。
happen to call resolve.
如果我们想的话我们可以叫它Fubar。&gt；&gt；扬声器4：是的。
We could call it Fubar if we wanted. &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Yep.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这来自JavaScript，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: That's coming from JavaScript,
不是从我们这里。&gt；&gt；扬声器4：好的。
not from us. &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：正在将输出传递给
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Output is being passed to
Then函数，它发生在完全不同的部分-
the then function, which is happening at an entirely different part of the-
&gt；&gt；扬声器5：我认为他们可能
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: I think they might
迷失在承诺从何而来的想法上。
be getting lost on the idea of where promise comes from.
和-&gt；&gt；Kyle：它内置在JavaScript中。
And- &gt;&gt; Kyle: It's built into JavaScript.
&gt；&gt；扬声器5：对，我认为这是
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Right, I think that's
他在这里被搞糊涂了。&gt；&gt；Kyle：I
where he's confused here. &gt;&gt; Kyle: I
除了说它内置于JavaScript之外，我不知道还能说什么，
don't know what else to say other than to say it's built into JavaScript,
这就是它的来源。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：ES 6。
that's where it comes from. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: ES 6.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：它是在ES 6中建造的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: It's built in the ES 6.
没错。&gt；&gt；Kyle：如果
That's correct. &gt;&gt; Kyle: If
其中一个承诺行为不端并且失败了，它是不是整个流程都失败了？
one of the promises misbehaves and fails, does it fail the whole flow?
是的，如果这里的p1以某种方式拒绝，
Yes, if p1 here were to somehow reject,
然后这些处理程序中的每一个都不听拒绝。
then every one of these then handlers that does not listen to the reject.
它们自动有一个隐含的拒绝处理程序，该处理程序只是简单地传播它
They automatically have an implied reject handler that just simply propagates it
到下一步。
to the next step.
所以，这种排斥会沿着链条向下传播。
So, that rejection would propagate all the way down the chain.
因为我们从来不听拒绝，
Since we never listen for the rejection,
它就会坐在那里等着被观察。
it would sort of just sit there waiting to be observed.
它不是真的被吞噬了，它就在那里。
It's not really been swallowed, it's there.
但我们不会传入拒绝处理程序来监听它。
But we are not passing in a rejection handler to listen for it.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：这是新的拒绝吗
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: Is that a new rejection
当它通过当时的传播时？&gt；&gt；Kyle：是的。
as it propagates through the then's? &gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：所以每个人都会得到
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: So each one will get
一个新的。&gt；&gt；Kyle：是的，默认设置
a new one. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes, the default
拒绝处理程序，因为我们没有传入任何拒绝处理程序。
rejection handler, because we're not passing in any rejection handlers.
默认拒绝处理程序接收来自上一步骤的拒绝，并且
The default rejection handler receives the rejection from the previous step and
拒收。&gt；&gt；扬声器7：使用相同的参数。
rejects. &gt;&gt; Speaker 7: With the same parameter.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：相同的值。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Same value.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：相同的值。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: Same value.
好吧。
Okay.